[
  {
    "correctOption": "The liturgy of the word",
    "firstOption": "The holy Eucharist",
    "question": "The responsorial psalm is read in what part of the mass?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Concluding rite",
    "thirdOption": "The liturgy of the word",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Mother Theresa",
    "firstOption": "St. Agnes",
    "question": "Who won the nobel peace prize for her work in india?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Mother Theresa",
    "thirdOption": "St. Monica",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Purgatory",
    "firstOption": "Heaven",
    "question": "Final purification will take place in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Hell",
    "thirdOption": "Purgatory",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "1566",
    "firstOption": "The first century",
    "question": "The first official universal Catechism was published in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "1899",
    "thirdOption": "1566",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Creed, Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer",
    "firstOption": " Creed, Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer",
    "question": "The “four pillars” of the Catechism are?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Eucharist, Commandments, Scripture, Church history",
    "thirdOption": "Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer, Scripture",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Eucharist",
    "firstOption": "Baptism",
    "question": "The “source and summit” of Christian life is?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Orders",
    "thirdOption": "Eucharist",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "24,000",
    "firstOption": "556",
    "question": "One draft of the Catechism submitted to the bishops of the world resulted in this many suggested changes?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "24,000",
    "thirdOption": "3,000",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "firstOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "question": "Who is the “physician of our souls and bodies”? ",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Holy Spirit",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Our Father",
    "firstOption": "Apostles’ Creed",
    "question": "The fourth “pillar” of the Catechism focuses at length on this prayer?",
    "quiz": "CatholicFaith",
    "secondOption": "Our Father",
    "thirdOption": "Rosary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "14",
    "firstOption": "14",
    "question": "How many apostles did St. Paul have?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "13",
    "thirdOption": "12",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus’ second coming",
    "firstOption": "Jesus’ second coming",
    "question": "“Parousia” refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The gift of tongues",
    "thirdOption": "One of the seven gifts of the Holy Spirit",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Confirmation",
    "firstOption": "Baptism",
    "question": "“Be sealed with the gift of the Holy Spirit” is spoken during which sacrament?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Annointing of the Sick",
    "thirdOption": "Confirmation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Code of Canon Law",
    "firstOption": "Code of Canon Law",
    "question": "Ecclesiastical Law refers to laws found in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "New Testament",
    "thirdOption": "Old Testament",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Vatican City",
    "firstOption": "Vatican City",
    "question": "Where does the pope live?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Rome",
    "thirdOption": "Italy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Lord have Mercy",
    "firstOption": "Lord have Mercy",
    "question": "Which part of the Latin mass is said in greek?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "Glory to God",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Individual Catholic families",
    "firstOption": "Individual Catholic families",
    "question": "When the Catechism refers to a “privileged community,” it means?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Hierarchy",
    "thirdOption": "Parish family",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Ten Commandments",
    "firstOption": "Cardinal and theological virtues",
    "question": "The “Decalogue” refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Writings of the Church Fathers",
    "thirdOption": "Ten Commandments",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Six",
    "firstOption": "Six",
    "question": "It took this many years to complete the Catechism of the Catholic Church?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Four",
    "thirdOption": "Three",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Fathers",
    "firstOption": "Brothers",
    "question": "The pre eminent teachers and theologians of the early church are referred to as?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Fathers",
    "thirdOption": "Grandfathers",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Common work of the Trinity",
    "firstOption": "Parish finances",
    "question": " Divine economy refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Common work of the Trinity",
    "thirdOption": "Tithing",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Perfumed oil used during baptism, confirmation and holy orders",
    "firstOption": " Incense used during funeral Masses",
    "question": "Chrism refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Perfumed oil used during baptism, confirmation and holy orders",
    "thirdOption": " Blessed oil used for anointing of the sick",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Easter",
    "firstOption": "Easter",
    "question": "What is considered the “feast of feasts”?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Christmas",
    "thirdOption": "Good Friday",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Signet",
    "firstOption": "Signet",
    "question": "What is the name of the ring the Bishop wears?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Fisherman Ring",
    "thirdOption": "Apostle ring",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Honor your father and Mother.",
    "firstOption": "Don\u0027t kill",
    "question": "What is the fourth commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Honor your father and Mother.",
    "thirdOption": "Don\u0027t commit adultery. ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Saul",
    "firstOption": "David",
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Solomon",
    "thirdOption": "Saul",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Terah",
    "firstOption": "Terah",
    "question": "Who was the father of Abraham?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Tamah",
    "thirdOption": "Ramah",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Good news",
    "firstOption": "Good news",
    "question": "What does the word gospel mean?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Word of God",
    "thirdOption": "Jesus Speaking",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Unknown",
    "firstOption": "Unknown",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Hebrew?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Paul",
    "thirdOption": "John",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus",
    "firstOption": "Peter",
    "question": "Who fed people with bread and fish in the Gospels?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Samuel",
    "thirdOption": "Jesus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Samson",
    "firstOption": "Peter",
    "question": "Who is the strongest man in the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Samson",
    "thirdOption": "Jesus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Judas",
    "firstOption": "Judas",
    "question": "Who betrayed Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Simon",
    "thirdOption": "Thomas",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Cain",
    "firstOption": "Adam",
    "question": "Who is the first to be born in the world?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Cain",
    "thirdOption": "",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Anna",
    "firstOption": "Theresa",
    "question": "Who is the mother of Mary (mother of Jesus)?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Elizerbeth",
    "thirdOption": "Anna",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "700",
    "firstOption": "700",
    "question": "How many wives did Solomon have?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "500",
    "thirdOption": "300",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Rebecca",
    "firstOption": "Jezebel",
    "question": "Who is the first woman to wear earring in the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Rebecca",
    "thirdOption": "Monica",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Three",
    "firstOption": "Three",
    "question": "How many days and nights did Jonah stay in the belly of the big fish?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Two",
    "thirdOption": "One",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Malachi",
    "firstOption": "Malachi",
    "question": "Who was the last prophet of the old testament?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Zephiniah",
    "thirdOption": "Habakkuk",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Methuselah",
    "firstOption": "Enoch",
    "question": "What is the name of the Oldest man in the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Methuselah",
    "thirdOption": "Adam",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "David",
    "firstOption": "Saul",
    "question": "Who killed Goliath?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "David",
    "thirdOption": "Solomon",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Egypt",
    "firstOption": "Ethiopia",
    "question": "From which country did Moses help the Israelites escape from?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Egypt",
    "thirdOption": "Jerusalem",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Green",
    "firstOption": "Red",
    "question": "What is the first color mentioned in the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Blue",
    "thirdOption": "Green",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Moses",
    "firstOption": "Moses",
    "question": "Who was given his name because he was drawn out of water?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Abraham",
    "thirdOption": "Aaron",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Benjamin",
    "firstOption": "Reuben",
    "question": "Which son did Jacob not send to Egypt for grain during famine?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Benjamin",
    "thirdOption": "Levi",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Rehab",
    "firstOption": "Rehab",
    "question": "Who hid two spies but denied their whereabouts?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Rebecca",
    "thirdOption": "Sarah",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Isaac",
    "firstOption": "Ishmael",
    "question": "Who\u0027s name means laughter?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Jacob",
    "thirdOption": "Isaac",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jacob",
    "firstOption": "Esau",
    "question": "Who stole his brother\u0027s blessing?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Rebecca",
    "thirdOption": "Jacob",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Tongue",
    "firstOption": "Tongue",
    "question": "What part of the body was referred to as a sword?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Teeth",
    "thirdOption": "Leg",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "40",
    "firstOption": "20",
    "question": "How many days and nights did Jesus fast?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "40",
    "thirdOption": "30",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "River Jordan",
    "firstOption": "Red sea",
    "question": "Where was Jesus baptised?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "River Jordan",
    "thirdOption": "River Nile",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "God will never flood the earth again?",
    "firstOption": "God will give him all his desires",
    "question": "What was God covenant with Noah?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "God will never flood the earth again?",
    "thirdOption": "God will make him rich",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Judges",
    "firstOption": "Judges",
    "question": "What book comes after Joshua?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Ruth",
    "thirdOption": "Samuel",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Leviticus",
    "firstOption": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "What book comes after Exodus?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Leviticus",
    "thirdOption": "Numbers",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "James",
    "firstOption": "James",
    "question": "What book comes after Hebrew?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Peter",
    "thirdOption": "Jude",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "",
    "firstOption": "Psalm 32",
    "question": "Which psalm has this phrase \"He makes me lie down in green pastures\"?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Psalm 23",
    "thirdOption": "Psalm 51",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Lord\u0027s prayer",
    "firstOption": "Divine Mercy",
    "question": "What is the name of the prayer Jesus taught his apostles?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Tantum Egro",
    "thirdOption": "The Lord\u0027s prayer",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Absalom",
    "firstOption": "Absalom",
    "question": "Which of David sons rebelled against him?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Andojah",
    "thirdOption": "Solomon",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Carpenter",
    "firstOption": "Plumber",
    "question": "What work did Jesus earthly father do?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Carpenter",
    "thirdOption": "Driver",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Hid it in the ground",
    "firstOption": "Invested with it",
    "question": "In one of Jesus prarables, the man who received one talent did what with it?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Dashed it out",
    "thirdOption": "Hid it in the ground",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Matthew",
    "firstOption": "Luke",
    "question": "Which New testament book has Jesus sermon on the mount?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Matthew",
    "thirdOption": "Mark",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Ishmael",
    "firstOption": "Isaac",
    "question": "What is the name of Hagar\u0027s son?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Ishmael",
    "thirdOption": "Solomon",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "God told him to strike a rock",
    "firstOption": "He prayed for rain ",
    "question": "When there was no water for the Israelites to drink in the wilderness, how did Moses provide water?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "He bought water ",
    "thirdOption": "God told him to strike a rock",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Crucifixion",
    "firstOption": "Amputation",
    "question": "What method did the Romans kill Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Beheading",
    "thirdOption": "Crucifixion",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Fifth",
    "firstOption": "Fifth",
    "question": "What day of creation did God create birds?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Sixth",
    "thirdOption": "Seveth",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jethro",
    "firstOption": "Zachariah",
    "question": "What is the name of the priest of Midian (Moses father in-law)?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Jethro",
    "thirdOption": "Hurt",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Built a golden calf",
    "firstOption": "Prayed",
    "question": "What did the Israelites do when Moses was receiving the ten commandments?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Built a golden calf",
    "thirdOption": "Fasted",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Pentecost",
    "firstOption": "Passover",
    "question": "On what day did the disciples of Christ receive the holy spirit and spoke in tongues?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Prayer",
    "thirdOption": "Pentecost",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Locusts and Wild Honey",
    "firstOption": "Rat meat",
    "question": "What type of insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Locusts and Wild Honey",
    "thirdOption": "Milk",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Peter and Andrew",
    "firstOption": "Peter and Andrew",
    "question": "Who were the first apostles called to follow Jesus?",
    "quiz": "",
    "secondOption": "James and John",
    "thirdOption": "Matthew and Mark",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "5000",
    "firstOption": "3000",
    "question": "How many people did Jesus feed with five loaves of bread and two fish? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "4500",
    "thirdOption": "5000",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Wisdom",
    "firstOption": "Wisdom",
    "question": "What did King Solomon ask God to give him?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Knowledge",
    "thirdOption": "Understanding",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Simeon",
    "firstOption": "Anna",
    "question": "Who recognized Jesus as the Messiah when he was presented at the Temple as a baby? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Simeon",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "firstOption": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "question": "Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after the crucifixion? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Barnabbas",
    "thirdOption": "Nicodemus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Malta",
    "firstOption": "Patmos",
    "question": "Paul was shipwrecked on what island? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Sinai",
    "thirdOption": "Malta",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "2 John",
    "firstOption": "2 John",
    "question": "What is the shortest book in the New Testament? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "1 John",
    "thirdOption": "3 John",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Damascus",
    "firstOption": "Malta",
    "question": "To what city was Saul traveling when he encountered a great and blinding light? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Damascus",
    "thirdOption": "Africa",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Priest",
    "firstOption": "Priest",
    "question": "Who was the first person to come upon the injured man in the parable of the Good Samaritan? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Levite",
    "thirdOption": "Samaritan",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Christ\u0027s",
    "firstOption": "God",
    "question": "Whose example does Paul say Christians should follow in Chapter 5 of Ephesians? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "His",
    "thirdOption": "Christ\u0027s",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "12",
    "firstOption": "11",
    "question": "After Jesus fed 5,000+ people with two fish and five loaves of bread, how many baskets were left over? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "12",
    "thirdOption": "13",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Love",
    "firstOption": "Hope",
    "question": "What does Paul say may “abound more and more in knowledge and in all judgment?”",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Faith",
    "thirdOption": "Love",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Benjamin",
    "firstOption": "Benjamin",
    "question": "What tribe is Paul from? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Reuben",
    "thirdOption": "Levi",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesse",
    "firstOption": "Isaiah",
    "question": "Who is the father of David?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Jesse",
    "thirdOption": "Paul",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Those who hunger and thirst for righteousness",
    "firstOption": "The poor",
    "question": "According to the Beatitudes who will be filled? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Those who hunger and thirst for righteousness",
    "thirdOption": "Those who morn",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Fisherman",
    "firstOption": "Hunter",
    "question": "What does Simon Peter do for a living before he becomes an apostle? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Carpenter",
    "thirdOption": "Fisherman",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "From the angel Gabriel",
    "firstOption": "From the angel Gabriel",
    "question": "In the Gospel of Mark, how does the Virgin Mary learn of her pregnancy? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "From Angel Raphael",
    "thirdOption": "From Simeon",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Saul",
    "firstOption": "Paul",
    "question": "By what name is Paul of Tarsus known before he begins his missionary activity? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Saul",
    "thirdOption": "Bar Jesus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Caiphas",
    "firstOption": "Caiphas",
    "question": "Who is the high priest of Jerusalem who put Jesus on trial? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Herod",
    "thirdOption": "Pilate",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Thomas",
    "firstOption": "Matthew",
    "question": "In the Gospel According to John, which of the apostles doubts Jesus’s resurrection until he sees Jesus with his own eyes? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "John",
    "thirdOption": "Thomas",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "He kisses him",
    "firstOption": "He Points him",
    "question": "How does Judas signal Jesus’s identity to the Roman officials? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "He hugs him",
    "thirdOption": "He kisses him",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus suffering and death",
    "firstOption": "Jesus’s entry into Jerusalem before his death",
    "question": "When Christians observe Palm Sunday, what biblical narrative are they celebrating? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Jesus suffering and death",
    "thirdOption": "Jesus trial",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Gospels",
    "firstOption": "Septuagint",
    "question": "What is the common name given to the first four books of the New Testament?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "The Gospels",
    "thirdOption": "The deuterocanonicals",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Luke",
    "firstOption": "Mark",
    "question": "Who wrote the Acts of the apostles?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Luke",
    "thirdOption": "John",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Ham",
    "firstOption": "Ram",
    "question": "Who is the first person to see his father nakedness?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Ham",
    "thirdOption": "Ramma",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "37",
    "firstOption": "37",
    "question": "Which wood has been used by Noah to build the ark?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "38",
    "thirdOption": "39",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Purple",
    "firstOption": "Red and Yellow",
    "question": "What color of vestment does the priest wear during Lent or Advent?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Purple",
    "thirdOption": "Green",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Death",
    "firstOption": "Death",
    "question": "Who sat on the pale Horse of Revelation 6?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "The King",
    "thirdOption": "Sin",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "They sold Him",
    "firstOption": "They killed him",
    "question": "What did Joseph\u0027s brothers do to get rid of him?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "They sold Him",
    "thirdOption": "They buried him",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "",
    "firstOption": "Levi",
    "question": "To which tribe did Jesus belong?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Judah",
    "thirdOption": "Joseph",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "James",
    "firstOption": "Levi",
    "question": "Name a son of Zebedee?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Simon",
    "thirdOption": "James",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Love them and Pray for them",
    "firstOption": "Preach to them",
    "question": "According to Jesus, how do we treat our Enemies?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Avoid them",
    "thirdOption": "Love them and Pray for them",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Walking on water",
    "firstOption": "Raising Lazarus from dead",
    "question": "What miracle did Jesus perform when he said \"It is I, do not he afraid\"?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Walking on water",
    "thirdOption": "Turning water into wine",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Nehimiah",
    "firstOption": "Psalms",
    "question": "What book comes after Ezra?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Job",
    "thirdOption": "Nehimiah",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "1 Chronicles",
    "firstOption": "Ezra",
    "question": "What book comes after 2 Kings?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "1 Samuel",
    "thirdOption": "1 Chronicles",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "In-law",
    "firstOption": "Sister",
    "question": "How is Ruth related to Naomi?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Neighbor",
    "thirdOption": "In-law",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil",
    "firstOption": "Tree of destruction",
    "question": "Of what, specifically was not allowed to eat in the Garden of Eden?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil",
    "thirdOption": "The tree of Wisdom",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Washed their feet",
    "firstOption": "Washed their feet",
    "question": "What did Jesus do to each of the disciples during the Last Supper? ",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Thanked them for their kindness",
    "thirdOption": "Prayed for them",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Take no thought of it",
    "firstOption": "Take no thought of it",
    "question": "What did Jesus say about tomorrow in him sermon on the mount?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "It will end ",
    "thirdOption": "Have good plans for tomorrow",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Commanded the Spirit to leave her.",
    "firstOption": "Commanded the Spirit to leave her.",
    "question": "What did Paul do to the soothsayer that made her masters unhappy?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Cursed the spirit",
    "thirdOption": "Praised the spirit ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Eve",
    "firstOption": "Sarah",
    "question": "Who is the first Mother mentioned in the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Jezebel",
    "thirdOption": "Eve",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Gold",
    "firstOption": "Gold",
    "question": "In the New Jerusalem described in Revelation, what are the twelve gates made from?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Bronze",
    "thirdOption": "Pearl",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Light of the world",
    "firstOption": "Immanuel",
    "question": "Which one of these is not a title of Jesus Christ?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Holy One of Israel",
    "thirdOption": "Light of the world",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Patmos",
    "firstOption": "Malta",
    "question": "On what island was John when he was given the vision of Revelation?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Patmos",
    "thirdOption": "Rome",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Miletus",
    "firstOption": "Philadelphia",
    "question": "Which of these is not one of the churches of Asia Minor?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Ephesus",
    "thirdOption": "Miletus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "7",
    "firstOption": "4",
    "question": "How many churches of Asia Minor were there?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "11",
    "thirdOption": "7",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Adam",
    "firstOption": "Adam",
    "question": "Who is the father of Seth?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Cain",
    "thirdOption": "Enoch",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "2 years",
    "firstOption": "2 years",
    "question": "During Paul\u0027s third missionary journey, roughly for how long did he minister in the school of Tyrannus at Ephesus?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "4 years",
    "thirdOption": "1 year",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Philippi",
    "firstOption": "Paphos",
    "question": "Paul and Silas were imprisoned during the second missionary journey, but in what city did this happen?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Philippi",
    "thirdOption": "Antioch",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Barnabas",
    "firstOption": "Barnabas",
    "question": "Who went with Paul on his first missionary journey?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Mark",
    "thirdOption": "Luke",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "40",
    "firstOption": "20",
    "question": "For how many days did Jesus appear to his disciples after his resurrection?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "30",
    "thirdOption": "40",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Golgotha",
    "firstOption": "Gethsemane",
    "question": "Where was Jesus crucified?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Golgotha",
    "thirdOption": "Mount of Olives",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Dipped a piece of bread and passed it to him",
    "firstOption": "Washed his feet",
    "question": "How did Jesus reveal the one who would betray him?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Dipped a piece of bread and passed it to him",
    "thirdOption": "Poured out the wine and passed it to him",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Moses and Elijah",
    "firstOption": "James and John",
    "question": "Which two Old Testament characters appeared with Jesus at the transfiguration?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Peter and Andrew",
    "thirdOption": "Moses and Elijah",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Zacchaeus",
    "firstOption": "Zacchaeus",
    "question": "Who was the tax collector that climbed up a tree so he could see Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Matthew",
    "thirdOption": "Luke",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Herod the Great",
    "firstOption": "Herod Phillip",
    "question": "Who was the king of Judea at the time of Jesus\u0027 birth?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "Herod the Great",
    "thirdOption": "Herod Agrippa I",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "27",
    "firstOption": "26",
    "question": "How many books are there in the New Testament?",
    "quiz": "Bible",
    "secondOption": "66",
    "thirdOption": "27",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Man",
    "firstOption": "Consubstantial",
    "question": "The English translation of the Catechism was held up for more than a year when some U.S. bishops objected to the use of which word?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Man",
    "thirdOption": "Concupiscence",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Simon Stock",
    "firstOption": "St. Dominic",
    "question": "Who received the scapular from the Blessed virgin Mary?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Simon Stock",
    "thirdOption": "St. Francis",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Abortion",
    "firstOption": "Abortion",
    "question": "The second edition of the English version of the Catechism was changed to reflect stronger language on this topic in light of Evangelium Vitae?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Death penalty",
    "thirdOption": "Euthanasia",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Revelation",
    "firstOption": "Gospel of John",
    "question": "Church teaching on a “heavenly liturgy” comes from?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Book of Isaiah",
    "thirdOption": "Revelation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Frances",
    "firstOption": "St. Frances",
    "question": "Which saint tamed a wild wolf?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Christopher",
    "thirdOption": "St. Joseph",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Joseph",
    "firstOption": "Christ",
    "question": "Who is the Foster Father of Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Stole",
    "firstOption": "Armise",
    "question": "What is the name of the scald the priest wears on his neck during confession?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Stole",
    "thirdOption": "Chasable",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "French",
    "firstOption": "French",
    "question": "In which language was the current Catechism first published?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Italian",
    "thirdOption": "English",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Seventh — You shall not steal.",
    "firstOption": "Fifth — You shall not kill.",
    "question": "Respecting and caring for animals is taught as part of which commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Seventh — You shall not steal.",
    "thirdOption": "Ninth — You shall not covet your neighbor’s goods.",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Three",
    "firstOption": "Three",
    "question": "How many persons are in the holy trinity?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Two",
    "thirdOption": "One",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Couples",
    "firstOption": "Bishop",
    "question": "Who is the chief celebrant of the sacrament of matrimony?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Priest",
    "thirdOption": "Couples",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Chasable",
    "firstOption": "Chasable",
    "question": "What is the name of the large coloured vestment the priest wears for mass?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Alb",
    "thirdOption": "Stole",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": " Come, O Lord.",
    "firstOption": " Why have you forsaken me?",
    "question": "“Marana tha” means?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": " Come, O Lord.",
    "thirdOption": "It is finished.",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "White and Yellow",
    "firstOption": "Red",
    "question": "What color are papal flags?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Purple",
    "thirdOption": "White and Yellow",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Baptism, Confirmation, Eucharist",
    "firstOption": "Baptism, Reconciliation, Eucharist",
    "question": "The Sacraments of Initiation are?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Baptism, Confirmation, Eucharist",
    "thirdOption": "Eucharist, Marriage, Holy Orders",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Argentina",
    "firstOption": "Uruguay",
    "question": "What country does pope Francis come from?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Italy",
    "thirdOption": "Argentina",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Rome",
    "firstOption": "Rome",
    "question": "Where did St. Peter die?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Jerusalem",
    "thirdOption": "Italy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Martin Luther",
    "firstOption": "John Calvin",
    "question": "Some credit this person with producing the first Catechism text?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "",
    "thirdOption": "Martin Luther",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The sign of the cross",
    "firstOption": "The sign of the cross",
    "question": "Every prayer starts with?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "The creed",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Extraordinary time",
    "firstOption": "Extraordinary time",
    "question": "Which of these is not a liturgical season?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Ordinary time",
    "thirdOption": "Advent ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Archangel",
    "firstOption": "Seraphim",
    "question": "Angel Gabriel is what type of Angel?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Cherubim",
    "thirdOption": "Archangel",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Red",
    "firstOption": "Red",
    "question": "What color of vestment does the priest wear on second of November?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Purple",
    "thirdOption": "Green",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Year D",
    "firstOption": "Year A",
    "question": "Which of these is not a liturgical year?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Year D",
    "thirdOption": "Year C",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "I believe",
    "firstOption": "Gloria",
    "question": "What do we call the summary of our Faith?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "Lord have mercy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "6",
    "firstOption": "5",
    "question": "What is the maximum number of sacraments one can get?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "6",
    "thirdOption": "7",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "First",
    "firstOption": "First",
    "question": "Believing in superstitions like horoscopes, tarot cards and clairvoyants goes against this commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Second",
    "thirdOption": "Third",
    "timer": 20
  }
]